<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on Łukasz Chrząszcz</title>
    <link>https://chrzaszcz.dev/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on Łukasz Chrząszcz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrzaszcz.dev/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why you should care about performance review</title>
      <link>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2024/02/performance-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2024/02/performance-review/</guid>
      <description>Apple stops all marketing for their iPhone&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip; quietly waiting for consumers to stumble upon and appreciate its cutting-edge technology and design on their own.
Can you imagine that? 🤔
New iPhone without advertising its ground-breaking camera features, synchronization mechanisms and computing speed. It’s an unthinkable scenario, highlighting the absurdity of expecting even the most revolutionary products to be recognized and appreciated without any effort.
Probably you&amp;rsquo;ll agree with me that it does sound insane, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Corporate Rebels</title>
      <link>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/10/corporate-rebels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/10/corporate-rebels/</guid>
      <description>Introducing the book 11 years of experience 8 companies 3 teams led&amp;hellip;
and still, one book can shock me by showing how discouraging some workplaces can be. Having immersed myself in the tech world for over a decade, I was under the impression that passion was a default setting for software engineers. I extrapolated that knowledge to other companies and jobs, thinking a similar amount of engagement, creativity, and drive toward success was present everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Culture Map</title>
      <link>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/09/cultural-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/09/cultural-differences/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that &amp;hellip; 🤔
Riding a bike to work as a manager gives you the best score from the team in Denmark? Riding a bike to work as a manager gives you the worst score from the team in China? Depending on your culture you probably thought that one of the above situations is obvious and the other one sounds ridiculous. I thought that riding a bike to work and behaving just like any other team member was a way to go for every manager.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
