<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on NerdyGeek</title>
    <link>http://chrzaszcz.dev/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on NerdyGeek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chrzaszcz.dev/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka 101</title>
      <link>http://chrzaszcz.dev/2019/05/26/kafka-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrzaszcz.dev/2019/05/26/kafka-101/</guid>
      <description>What is Kafka? Kafka is a popular stream-processing platform. What does it mean? You can think of it as a service that takes messages from one place and put it in another. It allows you to construct asynchronous processing of events, create pub-sub mechanism or distribute work evenly among worker services - the are many use cases for it.
Whatever your use case is, you need to know a few basic ideas about Kafka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Rebalancing</title>
      <link>http://chrzaszcz.dev/2019/05/26/kafka-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrzaszcz.dev/2019/05/26/kafka-101/</guid>
      <description>Recap In previous post (todo wstaw linka) we discussed what Kafka is and how to interact with it. We explored consumers a little bit, how they subscribe to topic and consume messages from it. We know that consumers form a group called consumer group and that Kafka divide messages among members of consumer group.
In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll discover how exactly does Kafka assign partitions to consumers and what we can change about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Docker</title>
      <link>http://chrzaszcz.dev/2019/05/19/introduction-to-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrzaszcz.dev/2019/05/19/introduction-to-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker! That’s a real buzzword today! If you haven’t had a chance to use it yet, then you probably wonder what problems does it solve and if it can come in handy for you? Have you ever struggled with a problem of installing new software just for trying something out? Doing this regularly can lead to chaos in your OS not to mention the extra hassle of configuring more complex or coupled software (Wordpress with LAMP).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>