<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book on Łukasz Chrząszcz</title>
    <link>https://chrzaszcz.dev/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book on Łukasz Chrząszcz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrzaszcz.dev/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Culture Map</title>
      <link>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/09/cultural-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/09/cultural-differences/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that &amp;hellip; 🤔
Riding a bike to work as a manager gives you the best score from the team in Denmark? Riding a bike to work as a manager gives you the worst score from the team in China? Depending on your culture you probably thought that one of the above situations is obvious and the other one sounds ridiculous. I thought that riding a bike to work and behaving just like any other team member was a way to go for every manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Software Mistakes and Tradeoffs</title>
      <link>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/08/software-mistakes-and-tradeoffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/08/software-mistakes-and-tradeoffs/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve watched Star Wars then you know that only a Sith deals in absolutes. If you are a software engineer, you are probably not a Sith at the same time (if you are, let me know in the comments section below 🤔), but do you deal in absolutes? In software engineering, just like it is with being a Jedi, every decision is all about the tradeoff, and not a single decision is either good or bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Atomic Habits</title>
      <link>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/03/atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrzaszcz.dev/2023/03/atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>Hi! Hello! Welcome to my first post on soft skills! If this is not the first time you&amp;rsquo;re on my blog, you know that as a software engineer, I&amp;rsquo;ve been mainly writing about technical topics, but I strongly believe that soft skills are just as important for success in any field as technical ones. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my thoughts on a book I recently read - Atomic Habits written by James Clear - and discuss how I&amp;rsquo;ve applied some of its ideas in my daily work, encouraging you to read and use such books as well!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
